When we started Flock about four years
ago, we weren't planning for AI when we
were building it. It was just that
Flocks came in and said, "Hey, why can't
this entire four first layers of
software infrastructure be mushed into
just one command?" Fast forward to when
AI starts picking up. That's when we did
feel a big wave come in because flocks
can sit on anything. It can sit in the
cloud. It can sit in a container. But
the local aspect was the most important
because that meant that these engineers
could actually touch and be aware of the
system around them. What is the value
proposition or the sort of the problems
we solve that you're seeing people kind
of use environments as code specifically
flocks for agents. The core concepts of
mix and flocks when we were building it
still stay the same. The more progress
we can make on making the output from
humans or agents or humans and agents or
whatever mix we have in between to be
more trusted, the more ROI we're going
to get out of AI. AI and agents, what
they do is they supercharge patterns
that we've already sort of seen in the
real world. And as you supercharge it
and you turn it from something that
happens once a day to something that
happens once a minute, any percentage
deviation from accuracy over here starts
multiplying and becoming
[Music]
usable. Hello everyone, welcome back to
the AI native dev. excited that you
joined us today and we have a really
really interesting conversation ahead of
us talking about sort of environments
and how do you how do you kind of have
AI code generation maybe meet the real
world you know where things actually run
and to help us dig into this and more we
have Ron Fronny who is the CEO and
co-founder of flocks as well as the
president of the Nyx OS Foundation Ron
thanks for coming on to the show yeah
definitely super excited to be here guy
uh so uh Ron just we're going to dig
into you know like why agents even need
environments and and where is this going
and how can different tools around help
with that? But just for for context a
little bit of uh of your world today,
can you explain a bit of what flocks is
uh and maybe a little bit of what Nyx is
because that's an important piece of its
background. Yeah, definitely. So so I'll
start off I'll start off with Flock. Uh
Flock today is is pretty much your
universal crossplatform environment
manager. With Flux it's open source. You
can create these environments that can
go into production, development,
building and testing. And these
environments are consistent. So you
define them once they can run on any OS,
any architecture. Uh lots of inbound
from very complex spaces like hardware,
security, AI and and financials using
the product today. And all of this is
based on the amazing magic that is
coming in from Nyx. So Nyx is today I
think the sixth largest project open
source project in the world over 10,000
active monthly contributors and Nyx is a
lot of things. It's the largest package
repository that's cross language over
150,000 packages all the way to its own
operating system. So you don't have to
do a OS replace but um Nyx is a lot.
It's a big community and it's it's
pretty great. Yeah. And I think it's it
maybe it's fair to say that like Fox's
roots were to sort of take the power of
Nick. of sort of managing kind of
granular environments and kind of make
them make it usable, you know, make it a
bit more you kind of have to get a bit
of a PhD to get going with Nyx sometimes
on it. When you do, you can you can do
wondrous things with it while sort of
flux is more about okay, how do we kind
of bring this power to uh to the broader
audience. Exactly. And and the way I
would think about it is that again Nyx
does so many things incredibly well. the
three things that flocks cares about and
and we really are trying to expose to
engineers and more developers and
democratize it. It's uh first of all how
how Nyx thinks about having a consistent
architecture across any pretty much
piece of software in history, right? If
it's a dependency, a library, an
environment, something that a agent is
trying to pull or run or an LLM, Nyx and
says it's all the same thing. It's a Nyx
package. So that's the environment
piece. That's the consistency in the
stack piece. And then it starts going
into the build area, creating a lot of
ROI there and how Nyx thinks about the
build and and pretty much
reproducibility and determinism of the
build. And the last space that Nyx
really is is shining in my mind is the
software supply chain security side, but
that's kind of um on the right, right?
In in a lot of uh kind of tracking I
guess of what everything that has
happened in the process of that. Yes.
It's interesting to think a little bit
as this will probably sound more
belittling than I mean it but uh is is
whether Nyx is like the alt messages of
uh the the alt text of uh of packages on
it like a lot of it is like it's
descriptive of I need these things uh to
exist to run but it allows you to then
sort of operate with with more
specificity but also in a way that that
thinks a little bit about when do things
get upgraded or or the likes. So I guess
is it is Nyx actually like a lower level
than than package management? It's
actually like more control and more
granular or is it better to think about
it as a as like an abstraction layer as
something that that sort of goes above.
Yeah, I think that's a great question. I
think so so the way I would think about
it is is folks that are listening are
are are familiar with virtual
environments. I think it's like a
virtual environment slammed into a
package manager allin one. So your
question I would say it's just a
different way of thinking about package
management. Mhm. So it's not necessarily
lower level. It's kind of more on the on
just on that same level with what we're
used to. Just it has a different way of
defining it because Nyx has a concept
that we internally in the community call
purity. Kind of a you know it's like an
interesting word for a package manager,
but it requires any piece of software
any piece of code that's derived into a
next package to come self contained with
everything it depends on recursively all
the way down almost to the kernel. Mh.
So other package managers might not
require that. Nyx comes and says, and
this is why it's like both a little
lower level and to the side of what
we're used to because everything you
pull from Nyx, you're going to be
pulling with all it needs to be created,
built, and run. Um, and I think that's
one of the core concepts that allow a
lot of upstream benefits like those
things that I mentioned about
reproducibility and determinism from
Nick. Yeah, makes sense. So I guess how
do you how do you see I know one of the
of the use cases for flocks that has
been sort of shining and growing is is
in the context of AI and kind of AI
environments and agents. Can you tell us
a few examples of how you see flocks uh
and and kind of these environment
definitions come into play in the world
of AI? Yeah. So very very early on last
year
it's like 50% of CHP's lifespan or
something like that. Yeah. Yeah. That's
what I mean. So very early on last year
one of the big waves because we when we
started flocks about four years ago and
flocks has a history coming out of one
of the largest quan funds. So there's
like a big scientific uh I guess I guess
history to flock with my co-founder
Michael but we weren't planning for AI
when we were building it right. It was
just that flocks came in and said, "Hey,
why can't this entire four first layers
of software infrastructure be mushed
into just one command where developers
back then, right? Humans don't need to
think about it, right? I think it's like
the the specentcentric aspect of what
you guys sometimes talk about." Um, fast
forward to last year when when AI starts
picking up and all of a sudden we see
this wave come in of actually uh the
folks utilizing and building like the AI
engineers that need to access their
systems. Mhm. Right. They need to
accelerate the GPUs all of a sudden.
They need to really work and and stay in
tune with things and that's where we did
feel a big wave come in because flocks
can sit on anything. So flocks can sit
locally, it can sit in a cloud, it can
sit in a container, but the local aspect
was the most important because that
meant that these engineers could
actually touch and be aware of the
system around them. Their environments
were aware of everything going on. So
they were aware of the GPUs, they were
aware of the hardware on on the machine
and and that created the first wave. So
that was the first initial use case.
Then uh the on the AI front, I think the
most the most active areas are
definitely on on on folks creating
environments for agents today because
just like a human flocks kind of
abstracts away the need to think about
the infrastructure. We do the same thing
for also non-humans and the thing about
nonhumans is that we're really trying to
make it a bit more again reproducible on
the output front. So we've seen a lot of
folks use that as a baseline, right? And
I think uh so so we're still on the
first point on sort of being aware of
the infrastructure. Can you kind of
explain that a little bit more? So I
guess what what does this awareness
manifest as? I I understand the need to
to reproduce what is sort of an
elaborate production environment in your
sort of local dev environment. I guess
that's part of the advantage of these
reproducible environments. I guess like
uh in in the name uh on it. But what do
you mean by hardware aware? So, so
pretty much the way you should think
about it is is is flocks and containers
they they work together and if we want
to we can dive into that but one of the
main differentiations between flocks and
anything that that that like a container
or VM or a microVM is that flocks is
able to run fully locally with your
system. So while it creates the
isolation via file path mechanism, Flux
is with the system in the system.
There's no abstraction. So you don't
need to poke holes to tell it to grab my
GPU or do something with that GPU. And I
think that was a very native initial
adoption motion coming in from AI
ecosystems that were just like we need
to use these GPUs for a plethora of
reasons, you know, in the initial
frontunning wave of AI. Yeah. Okay. So I
think that really helped. So uh I think
a useful uh uh maybe like alternative
that has not sort of provided what was
necessary was to say okay I want to
create these sharable environments for
my AI engineers but then if I create a
VM or if I create a container those are
too far abstracted from the hardware and
then Fox kind of solves that problem
gives them the sort of the ease of
portability while sort of actually
running on their machine so they can
take advantage of it which in the world
of of anybody kind of building models or
training models or sort of frankly
probably
inference you need that proximity um and
and I think kind of a useful mental
model probably more people are familiar
with containers than uh um than with
sort of flocks or those local
environments or exactly 100% and and the
one more recent right this like six to n
month which is again part of the AI wave
is is just that there's a little shift
and I guess there's two groups thinking
about local AI and cloud AI um and again
because of those core principles inside
of flocks and nicks there's also a huge
wave adoption of folks who are kind of
like local AI first where you can spin
up your models locally. You can run all
of that and that's that's also another
another piece to it I think. So so I
guess that's sort of another um
interesting use case to sort of
understand in AI. So this if the first
one was really like applicable to people
that are um maybe uh closer to the
science side of it, right? You want to
run on it as you get into inference and
you talk about sort of using AI. I think
what we definitely find, we see this in
our landscape and we see this uh just
sort of in conversations with uh with
kind of Tesla beta users and such is how
uh and I was about to say the word
disloyal, you know, sort of people are
to their tools like people are very much
in experimentation mode. Yep. They want
to move around and they kind of load up
their uh machines with all sorts of
things to try them out. They would use
multiple idees which you know was a
heresy uh moments ago, right? they're
probably more loyal to VS Code than they
are to Cursor or Windsurf or uh or
Copilot. And and so as they build
around, I guess the sort of tactical
advantage is just this um uh ability to
try out the thing quickly without kind
of messing up your system while being
able to run something like a local LLM
uh in your in your setup. So I guess you
I don't know if there's a question sort
of in there but I just find it
interesting which is it's of an era of
experimentation you know for many
developers right and that's definitely
another core benefit that we're we're
bringing in for that amazing open source
nicks right it's that the isolation
happens on the via the local file system
so you can spin up and spin down these
environments that have local LLMs or
local you know have everything you need
and any time you do that there is 100%
certainty of zero conflict on the on the
system itself. So you can have cursor
running next to you know winds surf
running next to you know five different
models all of them might be requiring
different versions of like of hund
different dependencies and and flux
would be able to actually self- sustain
each of them spin them up spin them down
and you you the agent the human don't
even have to care about it. Okay, cool.
And it's kind of a good time to remind
that Flux is is really sort of an open
source open kind of core actually more
than open core really like properly open
source solution. And so I think we're
sort of uh you know describing and kind
of digging into it. But I think that
gives the opportunity for everybody
listening to try it out but also for
kind of the sort of broader adoption as
uh as people experiment once again with
sort of uh with these tools. Yeah. And
by the way on that point everything I've
mentioned up until everything I've
mentioned up until now is open source
and free. So I haven't even touched
anything that's that's not yeah there's
probably a whole business around it and
all that that that that is its own merit
of it but it was important to sort of
know this is kind of readily available
to you. Cool. So maybe let's sort of uh
expand a little bit out of so like you
know flux is a is a is a is a means of
enabling some sort of uh I guess kind of
environment as code uh in an easy
fashion to define it. I guess you know
we talked about more tactical you know
AI engineers being able to work for sort
of experimentations. Uh maybe let's take
it a little bit more into this agent use
case that you that you brought up. I
guess what is the the the value
proposition or the sort of the problem
to be solved that you're seeing people
kind of use environments as code
specifically flocks uh for for agents.
So, so obviously opinionated take,
right? This could change probably 50
times between now and two weeks from now
when Deep Seek 5 comes out. I think
again I think that that the the core
concepts of Nix and Flux when we when we
were building it um still stay the same,
right? Because at the end of the day,
something is writing code, something is
deploying that code, someone is using
that code. And I and here's my
opinionated take. My opinion to take
here is that the more progress we can
make on making the output from humans or
agents or humans and agents or whatever
mix we have in
between to be deterministic, right? To
be more trusted, the more ROI we're
going to get out of AI because I think
about it as like human assist and human
replace. now not replace me in the evil
kind of way like we don't need engineers
but just more in the way that that is
actually giving me an engineer or me run
value right over necessarily building
another new feature on top of AI and
when I think about it this way today
what flocks does and what flocks
represents for me for the agentic world
is that is that bottom three steps of
infrastructure right if we can go and
tell you that you're just going to tell
us what you need. Flux is going to
create that for you and it's going to
have full reproduability, going to have
full isolation, no conflict, and it's
going to output the same thing every
time you give it the same input. Right?
We just maybe took a 10step stack and
told you that the first three steps are
solid. So I think that's one of the big
use cases for agentic systems where they
come in, they use Fox for those reasons.
That's one. The second piece is that
with flocks, it allows again just like
humans for the agents to run, test,
deploy the software on whatever the
latest and greatest is, whatever they
want to. They want to run it on some
Linux variant at 8 a.m. and at 10 p.m.
there was a recommendation that shifted
some of the model to go and test it
locally or in some like 10 different
case variants for a hardware and
software mix. The flux environment will
stay consistent. Neither the agent nor
anyone else needs to change it. And the
last thing I'll say on this on on that
general kind of p thread again on the
opinionation side is I think the highest
paid engineers are going to start become
to be the the the test engineers the QA
I don't know even know how we call that
yet. I don't think we yet have a name
for it, but it's the engineers that take
millions of lines of code and somehow as
humans validate it, right? There's going
to be like a validation phase at the
end. And imagine that whatever that code
is, as long as the flux environment was
the baseline for it, anything else can
take it, slap it onto something and run
it. So, I think there's going to be a
huge portion of portability that comes
into it that flocks provides today for
for agents. Yeah, I think so. So, it's a
very good point. I feel like each of
them kind of needs a bit of a breakdown.
And I think like the meta point that I'm
getting I think from what you're
describing which I is an analogy that I
like is that AI and agents that what
they do is they supercharge patterns
that we've already sort of seen in the
real world. So maybe before you could
rely on people kind of sort of keeping
their environments in sync and being
able to represent what happened in
production and you know create something
that is similar to what they created
previously in the test environment and
and as you supercharge it and you turn
it from something that happens once a
day to something that happens once a
minute then then any any percentage
deviation from accuracy over here starts
multiplying and becoming unusable.
Exactly. and and and like the simple way
and I don't know obviously don't want to
call out different products I've been
testing around I test different products
all the time and um I just I just built
a you know another app a few days ago
just to test the waters on where things
are and it's it's freaking amazing right
you as long as it's simple you you kind
of define the app you define it as a
spec or defined it with English instead
of with code it goes and builds it
hooked up you know the database product
hooked up all of that for me I only
needed to do the authentication and the
connections but then I thought about it
I was like okay this is super basic. I
want to now take it away and and now
build on top of it. That was that
transition going from agent to human
wasn't as easy as I would have wanted it
to be. And I think I think that's also
going to be a big part of it. And we've
seen it before, right? We've seen it
before with all the other waves. We've
se seen it from cloud to local or just
from one engineering team to another
engineering team. Exactly. Distributed
engineering teams are sort of the same.
So it's a multiplier but it you know it
may happen more and might happen like
agent to agent as well like two
different agents doing it. So so I think
like in the three bullets you kind of
mentioned up mentioned before. So the
notion of trust really is to say hey
there's a whole bucket of uh problems
that might occur because you set up the
environment incorrectly. So maybe in an
alternate universe or like another
alternative that you have is to have the
agent make up an environment, create a
bunch of commands that it's going to run
and and create that setup uh based on
some sort of instruction or things like
that. If it's doing it every time, it's
not going to do it the same every time.
And so can you can you just sort of make
that deterministic? So right, I think I
think that makes sense. That's sort of a
bullet uh or like a a bucket of items
that are that are useful and that
increases trust because it reduces
variability. We we'll talk later about
generating environment that's probably
its own kind of creature but at least
for now right so so that's sort of a
trust building exercise and then
subsequently when there's the
portability piece or reproducibility of
like okay can you you kind of hand it
back over to me and try to avoid the
works on my machine uh type environment
and uh and move it over. So I guess
that's kind of bucket two or maybe I'm
um I'm kind of mixing in your bucket two
and bucket three. Uh and you know which
which you also mentioned like
consistency or sort of consistent
delivery. So I probably blended a little
bit your sort of three bullets but it is
about controlling the variability in a
world that is naturally sort of
statistics to at least not multiply the
other variables and then uh being able
to uh do handoff whether it is between
agents or it is between agent and human
in a clean way. Exactly. And I think if
if again if we're looking at an
opinionated five-year, you know, vision
for for some of the AI native areas, I'm
like I'm like just like code switches
hands, human hands, right? Developers
move companies, they move teams. This
year, to your point about, you know, the
point you made earlier that folks are
kind of like jumping around between
different editors. I can totally imagine
us one year using one agentic platform
and then the next year, you know, the
the latest and greatest, the smartest
agentic platform is a different one.
Maybe because I'm pairing more of a
premium or whatever the new ecosystem
is, but I want that agentic system to be
able to tap into my code just like I
want, you know, the other senior
engineers swapping into team to be able
to tap into the code immediately. And I
think that's going to be a big part of
of being at least that's how I see AI
native in the future, right? Can you
actually be AI native in that in that
world? Yeah, I think that makes sense.
But I feel like to me that opens up a
slightly different question which is uh
okay, what we talked about up until now
is just about reproducible environments,
right? And then there there are multiple
ways to achieve uh reproducible
environments. Uh one I think that you're
referring to that's easy to disqualify
is a a specific platform offers you its
own reproducible environments. You know,
heck, it may be using Fox behind the
scenes. But if it doesn't show that,
then then for all intents and purposes,
you can't move from one agentic
framework to another if you've defined
your environments within that uh with
with no sort of standards. And so I
think that one's like easy. I don't know
if there's a ton to say is like we would
benefit from standards. The world of
open source is uh it's kind of there for
a reason. I think the second one is more
interesting which is uh probably by
default if I was to approach this and
I'm just you know sort of less up to
speed on the latest I might default to
containers and I'd say well containers
are my shared environment. That's how I
define you know my kind of
infrastructure my kind of production
environments on it. So I guess how how
do you think about pros and cons or sort
of differences between between using
these like a declarative if you will
kind of flock uh definitions versus I
don't know if I'm presenting it
correctly and and a build container. So,
so I think I think the way we look at it
today is that first of all, why not
both, right? Um, I think I think
containers again opinion Asian and I
know I know for many people containers
are a lot of things. I think container
inherently came in and solved the
world's problem about uh pretty much the
entire transportation layer, right? The
entire orchestration layer. I think
that's like where containers are
amazing, right? You have an Amazon
facility, everything goes into boxes and
then those boxes, guess what? Are really
easy to ship around because they're
square. They fit in things that are
square. We humans like square shaped
things. So I think where there's a
heavier differentiation is on how do you
define that container and what can move
under you that removes the
reproducibility and removes the
determinism and at the end of the day it
doesn't matter how well defined your
container is. And I think that best
practices around containers are usually
not that well, you know, not that well.
But even if you do define that container
as as well as you can, you still have
layers on the operating system that can
move from underneath you. And that just
makes it not 100 you know even nothing
is 100% reproducible but it makes it
significantly less reproducible to an
extent that then kind of again my
opinionation it doesn't matter when you
have such a hyperscaled world with
everything building code and building
10x 20x 100x code and deploying it. So
in my mind it's like it's pretty much
free to go and define that container
with flocks and now be able to make sure
that you have that full reproducibility
and then run the container and do your
flows. But you know two things once
you've set up that environment that
concept with flux two things now happen.
One whenever you want to move off
containers whenever you don't want to
necessarily use them for development not
talking about orchestration. I think
that orchestration is where containers
stay really strong. But I'm talking
about the dev environment that builds
that whole ecosystem. Whenever you want
to move off it, you have a common
baseline to move off it. You can move
back to local. You can move to the
latest and greatest thing. You can use
agents that prefer containers and agents
that don't. You become agnostic to it
and I think that's very powerful. The
second piece is exactly that where you
have that specentric definition right at
the base layer that scales throughout
time with you. you always have that in
your you know in your back pocket should
you want to pull it out. So in my mind
and and we have a large obviously we
have a large dock on this whole thing.
It's like today flocks and containers go
hand in hand and if you want to continue
the container flow great you just add in
another you know you just add in another
value point for yourself almost for
free. Yeah. Yeah. I think that makes a
lot of sense. I think part of it is like
AI is the great multiplier and uh you
know including multiplying of
probabilities and you know yeah I guess
containers it's not that hard right you
need to have worked a little bit
especially if you're sort of pulling
from latest as your sort of base image
that uh you know you you build today you
build next week you're very unlikely to
get the same environment and so part of
it just uh it doesn't take far to sort
of uh you know it doesn't take long to
to to get into that state right and some
of the some of just additional use cases
there is that you know we said about it
earlier it's like if if you need to take
a container into development and you
need to start poking holes at it then
what's the point of putting things in a
box right use flocks for the local
things that you need to be able to run
the things that need to be able to be
system aware and and and those more
complex areas and then throw it chuck it
into a container when you want to go
ship it out can you ship it out with
flux 100 flock and next 100% yeah but
that's not something that you have to do
today you know it's it's things that
integrate fully yeah and I and I Uh I I
do think I don't know if there is a
correct way to do specentric. I mean I
think it's a it's an unintentionally
kind of outra but I think it does rhyme
well with declarative uh and the idea of
saying that containers are an
implementation of of your environment.
And so once again you don't really have
like what it is that you wanted to do in
there. You don't really have something
that is a more higher level abstraction
of what it is that you're trying to
achieve. Uh and so if you go higher
level, you have something that is
inherently more portable uh and more
adaptable uh to different so we do talk
about specentric development being a
means of creating software that is
adaptable um because it it takes in the
relevant context and then generates the
implementation that is right for it and
maybe today in a good percentage of the
cases it'll be context but frankly even
earlier uh in this conversation you
pointed out for instance proximity to
hardware. It might also be that you
want, you know, a tool that has access
to sort of direct GPU access and maybe
containers offer you that, maybe they do
not. Um, but you you you have a choice
of doing it. I maybe I'll throw in one
more interesting thing which is I do
feel the pace that AI kind of
multiplies. You know, part of it is
indeed the frequency of actions. You
know, how how often is code deployed or
written or tested or runs. But then with
that also comes just the pace in which
the these actions actually take place.
Therefore the overhead that use of tools
happens. And so at TESL for instance,
we're you know we we we generate code in
many ways and kind of abuse it many ways
on it and we we try to have some version
control uh that tracks all these
different changes and we define that you
know git is a slowdown factor and you
know it's not optimized for that type of
use case and and at least in in a good
subset of cases we feel like we needed
uh the team has literally written a
service called notg uh to clarify that
it is not git but it does kind of feel a
little bit like git but it is fast and
it's local. It's nowhere near as sort of
fully featured as uh as Git, but it
allows for many more cycles, you know,
or or other capabilities. So, I guess
the other thought is depending on what
it is that you want your agents to do in
certain cases, maybe the ramp up and
down of uh containers, maybe the speed
of execution without it plays a role.
That's probably we're getting a little
bit into edge cases versus the norm, but
um still probably an advantage. No, I I
I think I fully agree with you because
I'm sure that you know cloud native had
a lot of meanings to a lot of different
people and I think it still has a lot of
meaning to a lot of different people. Uh
we were just asked on a uh procurement
form are you cloud native and I was like
holy
Uh AI native one of the things that it
it means to me now and the difference
between it and and other of these native
terms is to your point this the speed of
change the speed of iteration. Right. So
to me obviously as a biased person
having more solid ground to stand on
rather than shaky sand is always a net
benefit. So if that bottom rungs of your
infra are a bit more solid that speed of
iteration you're going to be more
resilient to it. And I think that's
another component of AI native because
things are moving so fast all the time.
It's not just about moving to a cloud
provider or being able to operate in
cloud ecosystems. Um I think AI native
takes it to a whole other galaxy. Yeah.
So I think uh I think we've we've sort
of spent a decent amount of time here
talking about sort of environments and
how like I guess the we first of all we
kind of skipped over a little bit the
fact that agents to begin with they need
environments because they need uh the
code that they generate to kind of face
reality right they need uh uh to to run
it or get some form of like execution
based feedback and and so we kind of
skipped over that stuff but I I think I
think that's a core part of that
generation. Is that correct? Like is
that indeed the type of kind of agent
environment you're seeing most uh most
commonly is I I I created some code and
I'm I I need a place to run it on to see
if it actually works. Yep. So I think
it's I think it's definitely in the
testing uh the validation the the build
areas and one of the things that I think
is is the most beautiful and we didn't
talk about Nyx that deeply but Nyx again
20 years ago one of the things it did is
that it it redefined the
SDLC because it said we don't start with
the developer environment and the
development if we start with the build
and define it we actually get everything
else for free. So coincidentally, I see
that aligning very well with agents
where it's like the first time an agent
really cares about this ecosystem is
when it's trying to build that code,
right? Test it, check for exceptions,
check for bugs, whatever it is. And and
that's why I'm starting to see Nixon
flocks really align with this way of
thinking. And I think that's why I've
also been seeing, you know, just giant
growth over the last year or two that
keeps exponentially going bigger. Yeah.
Yeah. And that makes sense. It needs to
be lean. needs to be kind of fast to
execute. It needs to be portable. Um,
and I guess what the other thing we
didn't talk too much about, but I think
I think is core is this notion of
reproducibility between the output of
tools. Um, so maybe maybe let's talk
about that a little bit. So you can sort
of think of three domains in which
environment management or kind of
environments as code manifest uh in the
context of AI. There's probably like
more like four, but at least you know
one is runtime. We sort of just spent a
lot of time on it. I was like I need a
place to run my code on. Um the second
is is the idea of generating an
environment. Uh and just to say the
third is about like picking an
environment or tool use of it and maybe
even learning over time. So we'll get to
that one but maybe let's talk a little
bit about this second one which is you
you have uh some tools you know maybe
all the vibe coding tools and uh those
they try to give you an output that
would run somewhere and so they need to
generate an environment for you. Yes.
Has that been a use case that that
you've sort of seen uh come up and and
al also like conceptually is it a type
of use case that you think of as a an
important one? So we're very much seeing
it come up. I think we're we're seeing
it come up as a newer aspect. Again,
everything is new, right? One year is
new is like three months versus six.
Yeah. Yeah. in the last one to two
months because I think a lot of these
vibe coding products and again I'm
making an assumption um because this is
coming off of like my weekend and while
I'm watching Bosch Legacy on you know
whatever building out apps I think a lot
of the vibe coding products are really
trying to maximize their their time to
market and they're not yet thinking
about okay how do we hand this off how
do we build sustainable code how do we
actually build like high impact
long-term apps and products they're
thinking about how do I release. I think
this I love this from a dinner we did
earlier this week. Uh Dana there was
telling us about building this bingo app
while in line at a concert, right?
Because all her all her friends wanted
to just have some fun. And that's
exactly what VIP coding is for. They
even optimize to try and have you
self-deploy on one of their you know
deployments if it's like uh you know
their website or whatever. They try to
minimize the amount of human interaction
that you have to do after that. And I
think that saves a lot of that long-term
thinking like what environment do I need
to set up? is someone going to work on
this six months from now? I think it's
like these minute apps that they're
optimizing for today. But in the last
few months, I think a lot of these uh
VIP coding um products have started to
be okay, how do we, you know, how do we
monetize more? How do we create more of
a sticky customer base? and thinking
about it and that's been another inbound
conversation we've been having so much
so that it's made us think also a lot
about you know what does it mean to be
this bottom rung of infrastructure for
an AI native world with all of this data
about uh what are the best packages and
dependencies to use you know what are
the fastest what are the most secure and
that's kind of giving us a look at at
what the future of like AI environment
creation would be like so that's you
know that's a quick well not so quick
thought for mine on on
So, I think it makes it uh I I I like
the analysis. I definitely like the
minute app. I haven't actually heard
that term. I heard like disposable apps
and all that. Minutes apps is an
interesting one. I think about food all
the time and for some reason it makes
minutes. It's like would you serve this?
Probably not. Yeah. Yeah. But it's uh
but you know, if you're if you're home
and uh and you're hungry and this is
this is what you've got to eat. Um so
yeah, I like the term and I and I I
agree. I think maybe even legitimately a
lot of the vioding platforms especially
uh are are just trying to kind of get
you to something working at the end. And
so I I guess that's both a a pro and a
con. So in the immediate term they also
benefit from prepackaged environments
because uh they can pull one off the
shelves and they run them. Although
maybe maybe they don't care about
variety too much. Like many of them are
very I'm going to pick a specific you
know superb base and uh you know
whatever sort of setup that I have. So
they might have like really uh hardened
or like picked a very specific
environment to run on. Um but then as
they think about repurchasability, they
think about something that is long-term.
I guess the other aspect of that is is
portability, right? You can imagine uh
especially leaning into like the open
source ones like all hands or or things
like that. Maybe generating a more
portable uh environment format so that
you can run it on whatever
infrastructure that you want. uh while
maybe the the more SAS environments
might bias and saying like look I'm
going to handle it end to end for you.
Um, and I think that's uh that's
significant. It's back to that sort of
standards benefits of, you know, allow
me to pull it up and continuing it. But
it also allows for for chains of tools,
right? It means you don't need
necessarily this one tool to now be both
the best at generating
um say uh the piece of code and
deploying it and another one and and and
also know all the way to like being the
best at operating it. You can say well
there's another tool here and it they
they share the same language about the
thing that got deployed and they can
continue on from there. Yeah. And I
think that's another that's another
strong opinionation for where we're
going in 5 years. I think again could
there be an AI Skynet that does it all
and also gives us a cure curfew at APM?
Hopefully not. But I think at the end of
the day, there's going to be products
and companies and agents that specialize
in their areas and therefore that that
ecosystem is going to be rebuilt, right?
You have the AI kind of like stack that
you guys have been creating and and I
think we're going to slowly start seeing
that, you know, condense into what is
the AI native stack? What do you use for
each part of your flow? And and maybe
the infra map and the DLC will look
totally different. Maybe it won't be,
you know, code, build, deploy. Maybe it
focus a lot about testing. At the end of
the day, I think you're 100% right.
We're going to have different products,
different agents that specialize in
different pieces of it, and they're
going to need to interrupt, right? Maybe
not as much as like 12 different teams
across a large company needing to build
out a product. Maybe it's just three,
but you're always going to have I think
you're always going to have that
transition because I don't think one
agent and one company is going to just
be able to say that they do everything
the best. Um I think you're going to
have a whole ecosystem built around it.
Yeah, I do think I think a lot about
sort of the right scope of tools in the
world of AI dev and and there is I think
I said this in like a while ago on a on
an episode where you you can think that
there are sort of two trajectories. one
is uh there's there's a a big brain
platform that it just needs to know it
all. It is the sort of the super
intelligent Skynet sort of environment.
Uh and and therefore because it's so
good at that we're basically just
dependent on it doing everything and if
it doesn't we're just kind of stuck you
know we or maybe we know how to like
become power users of that platform to
be able to do it. Um I think I think
that's a slightly sad reality because
really it it it limits innovation. It
means that someone with a great new idea
of a of a piece in the the puzzle can't
kick in. And there's another reality in
which we do have a chain of tools and we
allow different components to come in
and blend. And we had Matt Bilman on the
show uh from Netifi, the CEO and
co-founder of Netify. and he had some
great insights, but you know, he's also
very passionate about the the web
manifesto and about the whole kind of
open ecosystem and talked about how it's
also tempting to lean into the uh kind
of closed garden where because for the
same reason we've been mentioning a lot
this the stoastity, you know, the sort
of the uh the uh the non-determinism
that is also bothersome in the world of
AI. Uh and one way to do that is like,
hey, just be in a closed environment,
fewer kind of variables. uh and it's
very tempting and sometimes faster to
get to something working. uh but really
I think what we want as a development
ecosystem is we want an open system. We
want a system that you can you can hand
off things and you can have a tool that
is best of breed at a at a phase of the
journey. Um, and it's uh I I like the
concept of open environment definitions
because environments are like an
overlooked uh piece often times of
software like they're critical platform
and ops people are well aware of their
importance on it but I think for many
developers they're just you know they
don't think about them that much. So, I
I I I do really like the idea of of
leaning into and maybe investing uh in
these different agents at outputs that
are portable and and open, so standards
based. And obviously, you're you're
talking to one of the more biased people
coming in from Yeah. I feel like I'm
sort of saying this and you're not going
to disagree. You know you're clearly as
you're saying this I'm like if not just
for you know the fact that every AI
agent again highly opinated person is
going to be a every AI agent every AI
specialization whether your company's
building the best agent for testing or
the best agent for development of like
of high throughput you know I don't know
biotech um you know protein synthesizing
whatever there's going to be an open
source equivalent leave alone even if
you have the AI skynet you're going to
have open source AI skynet U which
sounds even I don't know if that's
scarier or less scarier than I guess
depending on who owns the closed source
one but um I guess my point is to your
point I think that's what you kind of
like just catalyzing me I was like even
if we don't have different companies in
the stack you're going to have the open
source and the non-opensource you know
best of class already um and being able
to traverse across that is just going to
allow us you know mere humans to be able
to go further. Yeah. Yeah. I I fully
agree. So, so anyways, we got I think
we're sort of very much on the
bandwagon, you know. So, so we want
talked about runtime and how do you
define things that the agents can make
the agents better then we talked a
little bit about output and how you can
uh create runnable applications
including their environments on it that
are hopefully in the sort of open
standard panacea that we want you know
flux being a contender for that. Um and
then I guess the sort of the the third
part is around environments as a tool uh
or or or something that we know how to
use. So, like I think as a as a as a as
a human developer, you know, you uh you
get better over time knowing which tools
to use, including like some SAS apps,
you know, some containers are going to
run that have stuff on top of them, I
guess. How do you think about I don't
know if the word empowering is correct,
right? Like powering uh uh agents with
uh with environments as a means of, you
know, better agentic decision-m or or
capabilities.
So, so we're obviously
spending a lot of time thinking about um
how do we how do we
solidify, you know, that first step of
infrastructure right above your OS and
and with that time, we're also we're
also able to see and put together a lot
of data on what it means to build
best-in-class environments and how to
build them and what runs faster, what
runs more repro reducibly, what's more
deterministic. We we're starting to see
all of that. And I think the next step
up is that, you know, eventually you
just tell you the human or the agent or
the human telling the agent will just
tell us or show us what they're trying
to
do. You're not going to need to say you
need Python 3.12 or you need this
version of, you know, some database or
whatever it is. you'll just tell us what
you're trying to do just like you just
told the agent. The agent might then
translate it to us at the info level and
we'll just output what that agent needs
in order to be having that consistent
kind of the software fabric of
environments at its
baseline. I think that's where it's
going in terms of environment creation.
That's where we'll be a few years from
now where just as much as we're trying
to make you just, you know, tell the
computer in English or in whatever
language what you wanted to do, the
agent or the human is going to be able
to do the same thing but just for the
entire infrastructure below it. And I
think that's where we're going with
environment creation where it's like I
want to, you know, I let's say the last
thing I just built was like I wanted to
build a a voting app for my family
that's dynamic and everyone can see
everyone else's vote for something. That
agent would be translating it, right?
And then saying, "Hey, I'm building this
piece of code. We'll look at either that
piece of code or the words in English
and automatically know what to pull in
for that agent to utilize." And it can
be by it can be by it can be b-sided
meaning that agents can come and say
this is what I'm trying to build you
know flock will just autogenerate it for
them or it can actually if there is
agents trying to optimize for it flocks
can actually suggest what's the ideal
environment and then the agent will
actually build off of that based on the
user requirements and the user spec. So
there's kind of like a dual-sided thing
that we're thinking about here and I
think that's where we're going to be a
few years from now completely and it's
going to be fully optimized. I think
it's really interesting because it
blends into uh into again the thought of
like creating an app and understanding
that you know you you you have actually
a variety of applications. I think today
we're not we're not seeing as much. I
think if you're building with AI and
you're sort of doing VI coding and all
that, you don't encounter that problem
immediately. probably because whoever it
is that is building the platforms
probably um they again they created a
very finite very uh kind of a carefully
selected uh set of environments uh and
uh and they just deploy in that
environment like so we have the the open
web you know you might have you know
deployed on a specific on netlifi you
might have deployed it on uh you know
within you know it's like a react
application like you're you're so it's a
very specific and then they only
generate to that confine
So, so I think like the problem it it
makes sense to me very much in in like a
future tense, but I think it's like a
pain that people are not yet feeling
today because they're still working
within narrow confines of uh what can be
generated. Right. Exactly. And I think I
think this is this is exactly like look
at our careers as software engineers,
right? It's it's so specialized. It's so
niche. come with the experience and
there's a reason where job descriptions
today require 5 10 years of a specific
language experience because you come
knowing which packages are the best but
you come with that kind of like world
view of it and I think we're going to
move to a situation where we're going to
be able to 5x 10x if not 100x the space
just by defining you know the best
requirements and defining the best you
like like these these apps are able to
create these minute uh minute apps but
in the future they're going to be able
to create 100 minute apps and 10year
apps and hopefully 100y year apps. So I
totally resonate with with how you're
looking at it. Right. So yeah, I think
uh it it's interesting to think maybe of
uh environment as as a bit of you know
partly overlooked because of of speed
part of the AI generation. So from my my
kind of different maybe lens engaging
with people building with AI, I think
today probably the the the top of mind
for people uh when they think about
environments is uh is environments as a
an enabler for for their agent. So what
they want is the to create the code like
create the code for me to create the
code they need an environment to be able
to run uh things inside of it and maybe
run some tools, run some tests and so
they're that's like focus and passion on
it. they they maybe they don't think as
much about the output piece because
they're in a closed garden and they're
just generating that. Maybe they don't
think as much about the declarative
piece because to begin with it's also
hard already to generate like specific
code that it's actually something they
anyway need to do which is narrow the
the fold and just like focus the LLM on
creating something. Uh and then on top
of all of those the the reality is today
that uh uh there are there are many many
gaps between uh the way v coding and
other sort of AI generation uh operates
today and any long-term viability of
these applications like there's no
thinking about maintenance of those uh
of those application. So and and and in
that process there's no thinking about
what happens when something in your
environment needs an update. Um like I
don't know
It's like seven steps down the road from
I not to say 70 of the problems that are
top of mind for me today and at the same
time they feel kind of fundamental when
you think about how would you build
things in software that is that has
longevity is that correct I guess kind
of representation like if you were to uh
guess at I don't know if you have actual
telemetry probably for this granularity
of division but like when you think
about people building environments would
you would you say most of them are that
like I need environments for my agents
to be able to uh test code that they've
created versus I want portable
environment versus I want declarative uh
like a script based kind of a prompt
driven environments. I think when we're
looking at agents today they're they're
optimizing for that minute app. They're
optimizing for for as simple as possible
low cost as possible. A user asks for
something pretty basic. we spit it out
with a minimal amount of bugs and that
optimization had you know I think
obviously I'm overstepping into the
folks building agents excuse me but I
think from a user perspective and from
like a let's say pseudo partner vendor
perspective as as the person you know
providing flocks and nyx I think that
optimization makes them care very much
about being able to spin up the
environment test it so that it's you
know that minute app is fully cooked and
then and then ship it out right they
they're kind of using that environment
as just like a transactional piece
throughout just putting the stuff out
there. Now, what I'm seeing the last few
months is a lot of them are thinking
about how commoditized those minute apps
are starting to become, right? There are
so many different products out there
that you tell it, hey, I want a voting
app that my family can see each other
live, blah blah blah, hook up super b
Superbase, which is amazing, and all of
that. And now I think more and more of
them are thinking about, wait a second,
where is the money? Where is the ROI?
The ROI is not in these minute apps.
Where's the differentiation as well? I
can always and I think that's where
they're starting to come in and say, "Oh
boy, we need some baseline. We need our
users to be able to export this and
start working on it super easily just as
as if they were sitting on the same team
with this agent." And that's what I was
talking about earlier where I'm we're
moving from like human assist to human
nicities to actual human replace in
things that allow me to focus on the
bigger more innovative tasks at hand
because all of a sudden this agent
becomes a team member instead of just
being that intern that we asked to throw
together the lunch, you know, lunch
ordering app for the office that we're
going to throw away three weeks from now
because we'll forget about. Right. Yeah.
And and I think in that sense that
becomes you have to think indeed long
term just like you you wouldn't you
wouldn't continue hiring you know a
junior developer who uh only built
applications that were suitable for sort
of a three-day lifespan or a three-month
lifpan and again there's use cases for
it but I think it's to your point the
differentiation the the the target
market and the market caps are going to
be very different for the minute apps
and the folks who are able to extend
that into into the large large
ecosystems. Yeah. Yeah. And and like I I
don't I don't think either of us kind of
mean to diss the uh the applications
today. They they allow us to to tap into
the magic. They're amazing. They do feel
magical and they they're an iteration
like I think you you can never jump to
the end. Uh you always have to uh build
it. Uh but it's interesting to also
think about what are the gaps uh between
that and and the future there. I think
uh I have one more question on
environments and I do want to ask a
little bit about that dinner that you uh
mentioned in passing because I know you
had some great insights from it. Just
one more question on environments. uh
you know MCP is all the rage uh uh these
days on it. you know, I know you uh you
have Flux Hub and it sort of holds a
whole bunch of environments that uh
people have there that you know, from my
kind of layman's perspective, it feels
uh oh, cool. That's a thing to sort of
slap an MCP front on top of. Just
curious like have you thought of that?
You know, I guess what's your what's
your view there? I guess when I think I
was going to say something, I was like,
well, shouldn't that be obvious? My my
head of marketing, Ross, very creative
genius, um he usually says these these
like has these things that just stick
with me. And when we started looking
into MCP, because Flux has obviously
been looking into MCP, he told me like
MCP, and I love this, is like giving a
super sharp machete to a random number
generator. You know, it's like giving
it's giving uh HAL 9,000 arms and legs.
So, I think from the MCP front, at the
end of the
day, I think it's just a more more
capable version of what we're doing,
right? All of a sudden, this AI has arms
and legs. this agent can actually go out
there and and I don't know, right, in
the real world, potentially hook up to
my email, answer my banker for me, you
know, review the tip amount that I
wasn't scammed at a I don't know, right?
Can access my bank. Um, and the way that
we think about it is that MCPs will run
software. That software has to be
provided upfront and reliably just as
much as anything else. Um, or it has to
be dynamically available for agents to
to extend upon. And and from our
perspective, that sense of reliability
just steps up again a level, right?
Because if if if I'm going to sell you
an agent that is connected to a bunch of
real world outside services, if you
don't have that AI trust and AI
reliability in it, that's just a more
dangerous, you know, random number
generator with a machete that you're
launching out into the world with your
name on it. So that's a obviously a
whimsical point of view from the flock
side. Yeah. Yeah. Uh it's interesting. I
get it. I think you're you're sort of
consistent also in pointing out that the
um one of the key challenges is just the
the degrees of freedom and just like how
many things can change. And yeah, MCP is
uh is like you know an API with no
structure. You
know that may or may not work. Um and I
think today by the way it does shine in
places in which it is still an attended
process uh that uh that runs because
then you give it tools but then if you
did blunder right and cut off a leg you
at least notice it before you say yes uh
uh and so that's good but it does feel
like also a good way I think people talk
a lot about MCP as a tool call uh
primarily and uh I actually really like
the resources aspect of MCP and it feels
like the uh opportunity
to make the different LLMs that run uh
aware and kind of easily access
hopefully frequently successfully some
environment from from Fox that we can
kind of pull down. uh is probably
interesting and kind of goes towards
that sort of uh declarative and again
we've been we've been having immense fun
with it like we've been hooking it up to
different things and bringing it
together and we're we're experimenting
with a few things with a few you know
with a few partners and and it's you
know MCP is is is great in my mind.
Yeah. Yeah. Its degrees of freedom are
precisely what kind of leaves room for
creativity and so I I think you see a
lot of people just trying it out. I I
would wager that it would become a lot
more strict uh or at least have an
option to become a lot more strict uh
over the coming year. So uh hey just uh
before we wrap up here uh I know you
recently hosted a a dinner event with
some of the top tech leaders from uh I
don't know if I want to name names but
like some of the top uh uh AI companies
both building on AI and building uh the
foundations for AI on it. Um, so we're
veering a little bit outside maybe of
the the kind of a flux or environment
lens, but curious what uh what takeaways
what what are the most interesting
topics you felt came up during that
conversation? I think I think one was
that, you know, AI's impact on developer
productivity. Still still a very hard
area, you know, to quantify and to and
to make decisions based on. I don't
think anyone's surprised by that. I
think even pre AAI we had a hard time
quantifying developer productivity and
actually you know there was like inner
loop outer loop uh lines of code which
was complete So I think that
that also made me feel better because I
was like you know thinking about that
very yeah you're always thinking about
it's like are they all like using AI and
seeing these huge quantifiable movements
and they're strategic about it. I think
in general it's like a lot of folks are
still working against that and that's
interesting. And by the way, another
example of the multiplier uh or like AI
is the great multiplier that it's it's
something we always wanted develop
productivity measurements and maybe you
know can we now do we have now enough
motivation to uh to track that and I
wonder when we'll start talking about
agent productivity. So I've seen I've
actually seen a few start talking about
that. Won't disclose that too much but
that was one I think I'll just call out
the top three that came to my mind. Now
the second was definitely that that that
glass ceiling that we kind of dripped
throughout where how do we focus on
generating more innovation on the AI
trust side rather than more innovation
necessarily on having AI do something
more or something better. And again food
connotations all the way. This was a
dinner. One of the things that was
mentioned from my end was like I want AI
to be my ultimate sue chef, right? I
don't want it to like make a meal and
wait for me to finish what I'm doing and
then make me check the meal. I don't
need it to make intrinsic like Michelin
star meals. I kind of wanted to cut up
bread very consistently and then go put
it on the table right now. I can go
focus on other things. And I think the
issue that a lot of us are still feeling
is that three out of five even four out
of five were the best models and
providers. They cut up the bread, they
put it on the table. On that fifth
attempt or the fourth attempt, they
place some rocks on the table. They put
some, you know, like machine oil instead
of olive oil. and that doesn't allow me
to fully kind of step away from that
area that AI is capable to do and move
over to do things and spend more time in
other places. Can I ask just on that one
before you go to the third? Is is is is
their sense or your sense that the the
part that needs to improve here is the
AI becoming deterministic or the humans
changing how we how we how we work and
uh to to be able to deal with
probabilistic. So I think that's that's
a great question because that was an
immediate followup. I think I think one
we do want AI to become a little bit
more repeatable. I want to know that
when I ask it to cut bread and put on
the table that like 95 again also humans
make mistakes, right? Yesterday I got my
chicken with butter and I didn't want it
with butter and then they went out to
the kitchen. There was no AI involved I
believe. So in centro
but we wanted a bit more. We want
there's a threshold. We haven't defined
it yet. It's probably more psychological
than not. And I think the other
conversation was like, do we need to
start just lowering our standards a bit
because our standards are are on humans
who have 40 years, 30 years of
experience doing most of these things at
a minimum, right? And obviously they're
older humans doing this. Do we just need
to say that, you know what, when I'm
writing an email response to confirm a
time, I don't care if it's missing a
period or or you know, it it was super
it was superlative in its response
because it's not human. Uh maybe we just
need to give it a you know run by Ron's
AI and I'll feel and as a society we'll
be like oh it's not Ron saying good sir
thank you so much I'm so excited um
accepting your formal invite for the 1pm
meeting we'll just be like oh that's
that's fine right but it just saved time
so I think you're on the money that this
thing has two aspects it's like our
shift of the psychological expectation
and AI becoming more appeal yeah yeah
and which I think is extra fascinating
in the world of software development
which uh we're we basically expect
software to be deterministic. Uh I guess
we know if you're experienced that it's
not uh because environments because uh
data uh but otherwise like we have a
pretty high bar on determinism that the
AI systems are not currently meeting
probably to to a degree we're going to
have to accept that but to agree they
need to get there was also an entire
conversation that led from it about like
you know maybe this minute apps are just
the new standard maybe you know 50% of
our thing become become a disposable cup
right that's like evil we don't want to
pollute the planet But maybe we do start
standardizing around some industries
having disposable software where it's
like every few months or every few
weeks. You ship it out with all the new
functionality and no one knows how to
reproduce it because that's totally
fine. And after a few months you ship it
out with all the new features on top of
it and you you know that's like a
standard question and a human psychology
question. Yeah. The third one that stuck
with me because I didn't expect it but I
I once it was said I was like huh I have
been thinking about this for a bit. It's
like it's career progression inside of
startups, inside of tech companies,
right? We're moving away from this. Um,
obviously in small companies, very
different than like the mega corporates,
but we're moving away from it. There's
an obvious career path now. We need to
kind of change our thinking there. And
how do we motivate ourselves? How do we
motivate our teams? How do we show them
growth? Right? It's moving away from,
oh, you'll do more, you'll hire more,
you'll be a manager, and then you'll be
a manager of managers, and then you'll
step up. And that's like a direct
correlation to scope and impact to what
happens in an AI native role, right? Um
maybe we don't need middle management
anymore. Maybe we're able to, you know,
have 59600 reports. I don't know. Um so
how do you motivate the individual and
how do you show them a path of growth
when it's not so obvious anymore? And I
think that was that was another big
topic. Yeah, that's a big and important
question. I guess that uh so so
brilliant insights uh Ron thanks for all
of the the kind of the the learnings the
sharing the perspectives uh both on
environments as a service and probably
conversation I should have left more
time for uh on the takeaways from uh
from that dinner maybe just sort of one
last question and teeing up a bit on his
sort of last comment on career
progression. Uh I asked this previous
guest and I I find it interesting. Um,
if you had a a child uh of 15 years old,
would you want them to go study computer
science in university right now or would
you think that's a good career move for
them? Um, I'm again very biased person.
Hell yes.
Uh, the the reason for that is other
than being biased, I think I think the
fundamentals don't change. They've never
changed in any wave we've had for the
past, I don't know, 50 years of
software. Fundamentals have always been
there. Yes, they've grown. they've
improved. But I think I think the main
recommendation today I give and and I
really resonate with is T-shaped.
Whatever industry you choose, and I'm
going to pick on software engineering
because that's the thing that you just
asked me. Yes, go study software
engineering, but make sure you go really
deep. You go all the way to the
fundamentals. I don't care if if you
chose Python because you like snakes or
you chose C for more some weird reason.
Go deep all the way to what are the
fundamentals of software? Why is it
doing it? How is it doing it? You know,
and then start going up, right? Because
that will always exist. We'll just we're
just adding another layer. We're just
now moving from higher level languages
to now English as a language to writing
code. But someone or something is still
touching the fundamentals and
understanding and knowing them is going
to always be something that's needed.
And no matter what the abstraction is,
it's going to allow you to always be the
most effective person using that
abstraction. So obviously yes on
software engineering and then regardless
of software engineering T-shaped kind of
recommendation for it. Cool. Well,
thanks super uh super insightful here.
Uh Ron, thanks again for coming on uh to
share your learnings and uh thanks
everyone for tuning in and I hope you
join us for the next one. Thank you guy.
Awesome being here.
[Music]